Inventory of the Buford Family Papers 1845-1895
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Buford Family Papers 1845-1895
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.132
0.10
2 folders
Buford, Paschal, 1791-1875; Buford, Frances A.; Buford, Margaret Letitia, 1835-; Burks, Edward C.; Burks, Mildred Elizabeth Buford, 1822- arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 03/26/2009.
Biographical Note
Captain Paschal Buford was lived from 1791 to 1875. He was the son of Henry and Mildred Blackburn Buford. He married Frances Ann Otey on October 31,1820. Paschal Buford was a farmer and a horse breeder. Regarding his military career, he served as an officer in the War of 1812. During the Civil War, he supported the south and invited General Robert E. Lee's wife and daughter to spend the summer of 1863 at his home. He died at "Locust Level", Bufordsville, Bedford County, Virginia, July 23, 1875.
Scope and Contents
Papers, 1840-1892, of the Buford family of Bedford County, Va., consisting of letters, mostly addressed to Capt. Paschal Buford (1791-1875). Other correspondents include his wife Frances Ann Otey Buford and his daughter Maggie (Margaret Letitia) Buford. Some letters to Paschal Buford were written by his daughter Bettie (Mildred Elizabeth) and her husband Edward C. Burks. Also includes financial records, wedding invitations, records relating to horse breeding and a note book, circa 1880.The following description was provided by the seller:"The letters are talking about travel, deaths, politics, some talk about the good and bad of having servants. Letter, 1845, from Edward Burks to Captain Buford notifying him that he is engaged to his daughter and asking about Buford's wishes and opinion in relation to it. Western Union Telegraph letting Mrs. T. N. Cobbs (Margaret Letitia Buford Cobbs) know that her husband, Captain Thomas N. Cobbes has died. 2 Wedding Invitations for the children of Captain Buford from the 1860s. Several letters and items dealing with Paschal Buford's raising of prize horses, mainly about the pedigree of a horse named Red Robin from the early 1870s, also about Knight of St George, Trustee and other horses."
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Financial records
Topical Term:
Horses--Breeding--Virginia.; Virginia--Social life and customs--19th century
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material, 1845-1882; id55483 (Folder 1)
  - Letters addressed to Captain Paschal Buford, 1845-1872; id54023 (Folder 1)
  - Letters addressed to Frances Ann (Otey) Buford, 1852-1877; id54025 (Folder 1)
  - Letters addressed to Bettie (Mildred Elizabeth) Burks, 1846-1847; id54028 (Folder 1)
  - Letters addressed to Maggie (Margaret Letitia) Buford, 1851-1882; id54038 (Folder 1)
  - Eulogy of Mrs. Frances A. (Otey) Buford, 1882; id54039 (Folder 1)
  - Horse Breeding, circa 1870s; id54040 (Folder 1)
  - Household and Financial Records, 1856-1882; id54046 (Folder 1)
  - Wedding Invitations, 1869-1876; id54049 (Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Notebook, circa 1870s-1880s; id54050 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1854-1895; id55484 (Folder 2)
  - Letters addressed to Miss Mag Buford, 1874; id54056 (Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Letters, 1854-1892; id54061 (Folder 2)
  - Envelopes, circa 1870s; id54062 (Folder 2)
  - Telegraph of Captain T.N. Cobbes' Death, 1895; id54064 (Folder 2)